DIKSON SAMUEL

Senior Software Developer

+91 97907 56025 | diksonsamuel11@gmail.com | https://diksonsamuel.in

ABOUT ME

A Software Engineer with over 7 years of experience in mobile and web development, seeking to further enhance my skills. Highly self-motivated and driven, I excel under pressure and deliver consistent results. A collaborative team player, I thrive in fast-paced environments. Dedicated to continuous learning and professional growth.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Developer

Sify Technologies May 2023 - Present

Senior Software Engineer

DoodleBlue Innovations March 2021 - May 2023

Mobile Developer

Skcript Technologies December 2016 - February 2021

EDUCATION

Loyola PULC

Master of Business Administration (2019 - 2022) General Management

St. Joseph's College of Engineering

Bachelor of Engineering (2012- 2016) Electronics & Communications Engineering

SKILLS

MOBILE DEVELOPMENT

(React Native, Ionic, SwiftUI)

- Extensive experience in mobile development environments.
- Proficient in both Apple and Android release pipelines.
- Streamlined automated release processes using Twitter's Fabric.
- Monitored and tracked bugs effectively with Sentry.
- Enhanced user experience with visually appealing animations using Airbnb's Lottie.
- Boosted performance and refined marketing strategies through Firebase Analytics.

WEB DEVELOPMENT

(React, Next.js, Angular, Tailwind CSS)

- Proficient in building and optimizing responsive websites.
- Monitored and tracked issues effectively with comprehensive debugging tools.
- Enhanced user experience with dynamic and visually appealing animations.
- Boosted performance and refined marketing strategies through in-depth analytics.

OTHER SKILLS

- UI/UX Design: Strong understanding of user interface and design principles.
- Security: Experienced in mobile security best practices and secure authentication.
- APIs and Web Services: Skilled in designing and consuming REST APIs and web services
- Version Control: Proficient in using Git for version control and collaboration.

PROJECTS

ISCA Content Portal - A content management web application for the TOI group to handle their image assets.

Star Health - An health insurance application which allows users to buy/renew policies and initiate claims.

Quantamove - Native iOS (SwiftUI) file transfer app.

Hellonext manage- Administration mobile app for feedback management tool.